Revenge is sweeter than candy.
Hansel & Gretel: Witch Hunters is a fantasy, horror,
action film directed by Tommy Wirkola.
After getting a taste for blood as children, Hansel and Gretel have
become the ultimate vigilantes, hell-bent on retribution.
Now, unbeknownst to them, Hansel and Gretel have become the hunted,
and must face an evil far greater than witches...
their past.
Hansel, played by Jeremy Renner.
Gretel, played by Gemma Arterton.
Muriel, played by Famke Janssen.
Mina, played by Pihla Viitala.
Edward, played by Derek Mears.
Edward (voice), played by Robin Atkin Downes.
Hansel & Gretel: Witch Hunters is a 2013 American fantasy film starring Jeremy Renner and Gemma Arterton as the siblings from
the fairy tale "Hansel and Gretel", who are now grown up and work together to exterminate witches for hire.
The supporting cast includes Famke Janssen and Peter Stormare.
It was written and directed by Tommy Wirkola.
In late 2010, after being approached by Gary Sanchez Productions,
Wirkola pitched the film to Paramount Pictures.
Renner was cast as Hansel in September 2010 whilst the role of Gretel was
planned for Noomi Rapace before Arterton's casting in January 2011.
Principal photography began in March 2011 at Babelsberg
Studio in Germany, and concluded in June.
Originally scheduled for release in March 2012, the film was delayed to allow
additional time to shoot a post-credits scene with Renner.
Hansel and Gretel: Witch Hunters was theatrically released
in the United States on January 25, 2013.
It received generally negative reviews from critics for
its weak script and gratuitous violence.
It was a box-office success, grossing $226 million
against a production budget of $50 million.
The film explores themes of witch, gun, witch burning, black magic, troll.
The tone is dark.